hello my name is grian and welcome back
to hermitcraft as you can see i'm inside
the tube and i'm pretty sure that this
messaging system is actually getting
somewhere if i throw the item i can't
even keep up with it it should go
through all the way i've lost it now i
can't i genuinely can't keep up let's
see how far this item goes because this
is the one from green to mumbo i then
need to finish off the tube from mumbo
to green and if you don't know what
we're doing we're creating like an
instant messaging where it's not really
a delayed messaging system between each
other so that we can send each other
mail even when we're not online as you
can see it is a bit of a long journey
for the mail to make it
and it got
it got this far so far
not too bad
i'm pretty sure we can make this go up
even faster by doing this
oh wait no that's the wrong way that's
the wrong way
oh wow
that's down i need to remember which
one's up and which one's down perfect
i can't swim this was a
fatal flaw in my plan
once this is actually done i can't
navigate through it
oh no so if i want to well actually i
don't need to i can just throw an item
down does it go straight up
that would seem to be the case if i
throw an item
yep it just that will work that will
work i don't even need to test it i'm
pretty sure that is absolutely spot on
so basically all i've been doing is
making the water go as far as it will
naturally flow placing some packed ice
down and then replacing it with a bucket
of water just after and then rinse and
repeat as long as it goes round the
corners fine
we won't have any issues i think i've
just made it to the end that was
surprisingly fast now all i've got to do
is make sure this floats to the top a
okay and
i've kind of guessed where he wants it
to come out i'm sure he can work with
this this is his mail room so
i'm sure he can do some redstone hockey
pokery to make this work i think we
should test it now by throwing an item
and seeing if we can race it there that
will give us an indication of quite how
fast this messaging system can be
it all depends on how fast i can fly
though as well okay so i've written the
message i think it'll be funnier if we
stick to paper that that way that we
have a very limited amount of things
that we could say we could end up
throwing back a book and quill but
where's the fun in that okay let's pass
on the message and away we go i'm
guessing that the message will already
be there by the time we get there my
takeoff wasn't particularly quick
but this messaging system could be
incredibly fast and it's not here yet
please don't tell me it's gotten stuck i
think it should have been here by now
something's telling me that it's not
it's not gonna arrive
my message got lost in the post oh it's
there it's stuck in here
oh wait is that no that's it arriving
okay it's much slower than i thought it
would be so it has arrived perfectly
fine
it just takes a good few seconds to get
here
hello yes this is a test yes hello
excellent so it works so the idea is
once a message is received it's going to
get sucked into a hopper and then a
piece of glass is going to be pushed
over the top of our main beacon to our
base now for me that's the one in the
center of the base and for mumbo i think
he's put one here i don't know if this
is his permanent one
or if he's gonna keep one in the middle
of his base as well but essentially it's
gonna change the color from the white or
bluish that it is to like a red color to
indicate that we have mail that way we
can always see now all i need to do is
the exact opposite to send a message
mumbo's just joined the game so you
might actually see what i'm up to as
well
if only we could make a little like
messaging system that just actually made
a jingle that goes you got mail i'd love
i'd love that
unfortunately i think we might have to
just settle with the beacons going red
the beacons have been lit
griendor calls for aid
i've just gotten to the end after going
through all of this and i can't seem to
get out
what is this bug
i
cannot get through here i think i'm i'm
stuck in this tube forever now i'm so
close come on let me help
this is ridiculous
what if i okay i just gotta place some
water there and take it away okay all
right that was much easier than i
thought i love how my first response is
i'm going to live here forever last
water in and the item should come i
can't leave again
oh this is so frustrating okay
if i put it in the sign that i could get
out
there's my oh my lights are broken
that should work
that should work just fine okay
now it's time to test if this works and
if mumbo will play ball with me okay so
hi m throw this in the other hole
t y
g so i'm just telling him to go and
so as soon as he gets this i'm hoping
that he's gonna read it and send it
straight back off it goes and now to let
him know
yes it looks like it's worked he's
sending it back now
the only thing is i haven't tested it on
its way back so now we just have to be
patient and hope that it pops out the
other side
and then the last thing to do is to link
this up with a splash of redstone so
that this will change to red
as soon as it comes through which oh
there it is
we got the mail
yes it worked
this all sparked off because i left him
these messages saying did a sample
whatever it doesn't matter i left these
signs because that was the only way we
could communicate when we were offline
from each other in game
so i decided that i was going to make
this instead and i think this is gonna
work absolutely brilliantly because even
mumbo can't know to fail to notice when
his beacon turns red
although
i'm pretty sure he could surprise me my
side of the deal is now complete and
it's actually been a while since i've
gone and checked on my shop so let's go
and have a look there oh my goodness
someone's made like a world war ii
hangar
what is this oh this looks brilliant i
love the look at this i'm wondering if
the shopping district needs to be made a
bit bigger because
it's pretty much full at this time this
time and we have sold all of our gravel
and we've sold all of the quartz
18 diamonds that's not bad at all quartz
is an easy way to make money i feel and
then gravel as well although i was kind
of hoping that i didn't sell the gravel
because i've now run out myself and i've
actually mined so much gravel
that there's none left in the area that
i was using so i now need to go and find
a new gravel place to be honest with you
i might as well just pop all of these
diamonds straight in here because
i use so many rockets because i'm i'm so
unconservative with them i'm very very
liberal
on the old rockets ah as the sun goes
down that means it's phantom hunting
time
as a little progress report i am now at
and i am closing the gap between me and
cleo and kerb because i'm kind of like
the up and coming uh hunter in this
scenario but there's still at least 300
more phantoms
than i have right now so cub is well
over 1 000 as is cleo so there's at
least 250 probably 300 or 400 between us
now i'm pretty sure if i'd started
hunting way earlier i might be in the
lead but it's kind of cool that i feel
like i'm sort of catching all speak of
the devil and he shall come there we go
bop him on the head
and it begins again everyone
actually
i feel like i've killed so many now and
i'm so used to phantoms that i could
essentially
become one that's right everyone i have
been bitten by so many phantoms i have
become one myself and you can call me
the phantom menace
how brilliant is this i look so cool i
wonder hold on i've got a brilliant idea
but we're gonna need to find mumbo for
this
there's still there's still chickens in
mumbo's face
i feel like they're gonna be they're
gonna be around a while aren't they so
the idea is we need to find mumbo and
hang around there he is we need to find
mumbo and hang around out of sight this
is gonna be so much fun so i haven't
slept in a long time now so
he does he has no idea what's going to
hit him so i'm going to stand around
here and i'm going to spawn phantoms oh
there they are they're up there
oh man they're all out of out of the way
i need to kind of keep on mumbo and just
make sure that some phantoms spawn and
then i'm gonna fly around with them that
is
so creepy isn't it flying around the
moon like that i really need those guys
to come down here but i'm sure if i wait
long enough they're just gonna spawn
here he's gonna see me
come to me my friends we must attack
mambo
[Laughter]
okay they don't make that noise but it's
close enough
if only i had some more i need to spawn
some more phantoms in i need my friends
there they are there they are
come with me come with me my phantom
friends we must we must go together
follow me there he is there he is there
is i found him come on let's
try and get them in let's try and coax
them to get mumbo hit
[Laughter]
you make a good phantom
oh this this has going to be one of the
most genius ideas i've ever had it must
be
i must fit right in
come my pretties
come with me
go
i'm pretty sure if i hang around him
long enough they're gonna go for him oh
no
well if you're gonna do it you gotta do
it properly haven't you ah the sun
[Music]
oh thank goodness i'm back to normal i
think
yep back to normal perfect subscribe for
your troubles
[Laughter]
uh that's what happens when you spend
too much time with the phantoms you
become the phantom menace i think we
should do that to a few other people let
me know in the comments who should be
the next phantom menace target
oh that was a broken anvil right there
and away we go
that was a lot of fun now normally i'd
start working on my base here but i am
pretty much out of white concrete this
is the most that i have three stacks and
i'm definitely gonna need a bit more of
that to finish it and if i'm going to
time lapse this i need to make sure i
have the available resources so i've got
most the everything else that i need
pretty much
but i'm out of gravel so unfortunately
i've got to do one of those dull tasks
of going to find some resources
flying through here is one of my
favorite things you just got to be
careful about the landing i'll show you
where i've been previously getting all
of my gravel from the gravel path in the
nether until you find this portal but
on the other side it's just a little bit
disappointing
as you can see
i have decimated the entire place
there's a few bits of gravel here
just left around but this used to be all
gravel you can see where it used to be
uh so i'm gonna have to find a new place
in fairness quite a lot of it has been
decimated
i think i mainly stuck to this area and
thought it was all ran
do you know what i don't actually think
this is the same area that i decimated i
think this is someone else's
completely different i think this is
completely different to the gravel farm
that i was using so i might have
actually solved my problems by trying to
find the original problem in the first
place now i just gotta grind away for a
few minutes
and we've now filled up we've got two
shulker boxes full of gravel and an
inventory full so that's not too bad at
all
that will do us for at least a couple of
hours
you wouldn't believe how much gravel i
get through with all that white concrete
and i sell it on the side as well
so yeah i'm probably gonna have to come
back for more at some point
uh
this is weird i've come across something
that i don't know what it is there's a
gas there and i don't know wait is that
a real guest
it is isn't it that is a real ghast
[Music]
what on earth this is
terrifying
how have they done
what
the heck
this is so weird
i don't like it but it has given me
access to a nether portal which is
exactly where i need to go
i need to find my way home i always
forget the coordinates of my own base
well it handily links all the way back
to here which is great because i need to
repair my shovel
[Music]
and everything is repaired and we have a
bunch of levels as well
i'd say all in all that was pretty
successful little grind that we'd
how
i wasn't even going that
you are kidding me
i wasn't even going that fast what
no i'm not okay mumbo i was hurt
i was hurt by the machine
the ladder killed me again i keep a
backup elytra just so that i can
do exactly what i need to do which is
get back to the get back to my stuff as
soon as possible
i was about to say it's great how i've
got some levels left but
i'm pretty sure that's not the case
anymore
thing is i normally fly down really
fast like that i don't think i even had
that much momentum
oh dear if i was gonna play a hardcore
game of minecraft i wouldn't make it
past the first episode i swear i really
wouldn't guess i'll have to make do with
seven levels for now at least i can now
replenish my gravel stocks oh it's night
time i am missing out on a night of
hunting
why is doc here all of a sudden
wait
there's a tag in progress going on right
now
there has to be
oh
there's a
there's a tag in progress
uh
um
i i've been tagged three times i don't
want to do it again
never again i'm just going to stay here
for a while i don't want to get tagged
i think biffer is the one that's tagged
at the moment
i've done i feel like i've done my time
i've been tagged so much
doc's there he's looking
i think he's looking for him is biffer
on a hunt i don't want any part of this
i am not involved i was so confused as
to why doc was here it's because he's
getting chased by biffer and biff is it
at the moment
oh there he is oh
no
i don't want i don't want any part of
this
no i won't be having it i won't be
having it i bet i have more rockets
i can outfly you
there's no way there's no way i'm
getting tagged
no way no way no way no way no way no
way
he won't if i vanish into the nether he
won't
suspect a thing
that was very close that's the last time
i followed doc anywhere
so we know biffer is hunting around the
shopping district
oh my heart is racing
do you think he saw me going to the
nether
i doubt he could have flown that because
that was a really deep dive through the
base not sure he would have been able to
maneuver that as fast as me i am so used
to that right now well i'm not gonna let
biffer being tagged stop me doing what i
was gonna do
i need to go to the shopping district
and unload this gravel into my cart he
might be hunting around my base at the
moment doesn't look like he's about as
soon as we hear her as soon as we hear a
rocket go off we run very very quickly
put this gravel in i know that i need
gravel but i also need an income because
there's no way i'm mining diamonds
anymore this is a scary time to be
outside i don't think it's safe to go
back to the base but i do think that is
a safe place to end the episode
today we went and finished off our
messaging system now we just need mumbo
go and pester mumbo to finish up the
redstone on it so that we can send each
other mail and we went and became the
phantom menace let me know who the next
phantom menace
uh victim should be
and then we did some odds grinding stuff
preparing so that i can build the rest
of my base thank you very much for
watching and good bye